<project_specification>
  <project_name>YouTube Subtitle to AI Article Converter - MVP</project_name>

  <overview>
    This project builds a web application deployed on Cloudflare Worker. Users input a YouTube video link with subtitles, and AI converts the video content into a well-structured Chinese article with a single click. It supports real-time streaming generation, custom generation rules, and chapter-level 5W1H structured summaries. The core product goal is to validate the "video content → structured article" automation workflow, providing content creators and learners with an efficient information organization tool.
  </overview>

  <technology_stack>
    <frontend>
      <framework>Bundled vanilla JS + CSS via esbuild. No SPA framework — bundled modules for clean separation.</framework>
      <styling>Modern Clean CSS (responsive, maintainable, semantic)</styling>
      <state_management>DOM-based state with clean separation</state_management>
      <routing>Single-page application, no routing required</routing>
      <markdown>Lightweight regex parser for chapter rendering</markdown>
      <stream_rendering>SSE streaming DOM rendering (real-time typewriter effect)</stream_rendering>
      <bundling>esbuild bundles src/frontend/ → public/. Worker serves public/ as static assets.</bundling>
      <port>Local: 34997 | Production: Cloudflare Worker hosted</port>
    </frontend>

    <backend>
      <runtime>Cloudflare Worker (production-grade serverless)</runtime>
      <language>TypeScript (type-safe, clean, maintainable)</language>
      <http>Standard Fetch API + Request/Response</http>
      <streaming>TransformStream + SSE (Content-Type: text/event-stream) for real-time AI output</streaming>
      <tcp_socket>cloudflare:sockets connect() for Webshare proxy tunneling (Free plan compatible)</tcp_socket>
      <security>Encrypted secrets via wrangler.toml or Cloudflare dashboard; no key exposure</security>
      <performance>Global low-latency edge network</performance>
      <modularity>Clear module separation — each file has a single responsibility</modularity>
      <testability>Local dev server support (wrangler dev)</testability>
      <port>Local: 34997 | Production: Serverless deployment</port>
    </backend>

    <youtube_module>
      <library>youtubei.js (npm: youtubei.js) — most active Innertube API library</library>
      <worker_compat>Risk: youtubei.js may use Node.js APIs incompatible with Workers. Fallback: raw Innertube HTTP calls or a Workers-compatible fork if needed.</worker_compat>
      <caption_fetch>Innertube API with official-like stability</caption_fetch>
      <language_strategy>zh-CN → zh → en (auto fallback chain)</language>
      <proxy>Cloudflare TCP Socket connect() + Webshare.io proxy (anti-captcha)</proxy>
      <reliability>Hard-coded subtitle fallback from src/fallback-subtitles/ (100% availability for demo)</reliability>
    </youtube_module>

    <ai_module>
      <providers>
        <default>Gemini (gemini-2.5-flash) — generateContentStream() + generateContent(). The default AI provider for production deployment.</default>
        <local_dev>DeepSeek (deepseek-chat) — OpenAI-compatible chat completions API. Takes priority in local development when DEEPSEEK_API_KEY is set (free tier, no credit card required).</local_dev>
      </providers>
      <selection_logic>Env-var auto-detection: if DEEPSEEK_API_KEY is present, all AI calls route to DeepSeek (local dev convenience); otherwise Gemini is the default (production). No runtime fallback between providers — the choice is fixed at Worker startup.</selection_logic>
      <streaming>SSE streaming output via DeepSeek chat completions (stream: true) for local dev, or Gemini generateContentStream() by default</streaming>
      <prompt_engineering>Dual-format prompt templates in src/backend/prompts.ts: plain text for Gemini (buildArticlePrompt / build5W1HPrompt) and chat messages for DeepSeek (buildArticleMessages / build5W1HMessages). Same generation rules, different transport format.</prompt_engineering>
      <response_format>Article text in Markdown + 5W1H structured JSON</response_format>
      <error_handling>Graceful failure with fallback content; provider-specific error messages (DeepSeek/Gemini distinguished in error output)</error_handling>
    </ai_module>

    <storage_module>
      <service>Cloudflare KV (edge key-value storage)</service>
      <purpose>Session context cache for 5W1H (no re-transmission of full article from client)</purpose>
      <data_schema>Type-safe structured session object</schema>
      <expiration>TTL 3600s (auto cleanup, cost-efficient)</expiration>
    </storage_module>

    <infrastructure>
      <proxy_provider>Webshare.io (free, no credit card)</proxy_provider>
      <proxy_implementation>TCP Socket tunnel via cloudflare:sockets connect() (Worker-compatible)</proxy_implementation>
      <anti_captcha>Auto retry + proxy failover</anti_captcha>
      <deployment>Wrangler CLI + wrangler.toml (Infrastructure as Code)</deployment>
      <environment>Local dev + production parity (no inconsistency)</environment>
    </infrastructure>
  </technology_stack>

  <prerequisites>
    <item>Cloudflare account (for Worker deployment and KV namespace creation)</item>
    <item>Google Gemini API Key (free tier, for gemini-3.5-flash)</item>
    <item>Webshare.io free proxy account (for bypassing YouTube anti-bot / captcha)</item>
    <item>Node.js + npm environment (local development and dependency installation)</item>
    <item>wrangler CLI (Cloudflare Worker deployment tool)</item>
  </prerequisites>

  <core_features>
    <!-- 1. YouTube Subtitle Extraction Module -->
    <subtitle_extraction>
      - Supports standard YouTube link parsing (youtube.com and youtu.be formats)
      - Prefers Simplified Chinese subtitles; falls back to English when Chinese subtitles are unavailable
      - Direct mode uses youtubei.js Innertube API to pull subtitles directly
      - Automatically switches to Webshare TCP Socket proxy mode on captcha / anti-bot trigger
      - Falls back to built-in hard-coded subtitles from src/fallback-subtitles/ when all else fails
      - Automatically strips subtitle timestamps and irrelevant markers, outputting clean plain text
    </subtitle_extraction>

    <!-- 2. AI Streaming Article Generation Module -->
    <article_generation>
      - Streaming text generation via gemini-3.5-flash generateContentStream() API
      - Frontend renders a real-time typewriter effect — content is displayed chunk by chunk as it is generated
      - Auto-detects Markdown headings (##) for chapter division
      - Preserves conversational tone while optimizing for readable article layout
      - Supports optional natural-language generation rules (taskType, style, audience, constraint) sent as `rule: string` in the request body
      - Shows loading state during generation; provides friendly degradation on failure
    </article_generation>

    <!-- 3. Chapter-Level 5W1H Summary Module -->
    <chapter_summary>
      - Automatically splits the article into chapters based on Markdown ## headings
      - Chapter titles are normalized: ## prefix and leading/trailing whitespace stripped before storage and matching
      - Clicking the [5W1H] button next to a chapter sends sessionId + chapter title to server
      - Server retrieves full article context from KV (no client re-transmission)
      - Generates structured Who/What/When/Where/Why/How summaries via Gemini
      - Summaries rendered in a fixed format: Who, What, When, Where, Why, How as structured JSON
      - Summary boxes are collapsed by default, expand on click
    </chapter_summary>

    <!-- 4. User Interaction & Frontend Experience Module -->
    <ui_interaction>
      - Clean single-page layout divided into input area and result display area
      - Input area: YouTube link field (required) + custom rules text field (optional) + Generate button
      - Generate button auto-disabled during requests to prevent duplicate submissions
      - Article content with automatic word wrapping and reading optimization, responsive to screen widths
      - Chapter headings clearly distinguished from body text with scroll anchoring
      - 5W1H summary boxes collapsed by default, expand on click
    </ui_interaction>

    <!-- 5. System Stability & Error Handling Module -->
    <error_handling>
      - Invalid link format validation with instant feedback on input errors
      - Subtitle fallback chain: direct → proxy → hard-coded (workflow never breaks)
      - Gemini API failures return clear error messages for easy debugging
      - Auto-rotates through multiple Webshare proxy nodes in proxy mode
      - KV session caches auto-expire after 1 hour to prevent storage bloat
      - After generation completes, session context persists in KV — 5W1H queries work across page refreshes for up to 1 hour
    </error_handling>
  </core_features>

  <database_schema>
    <kv_namespace>
      <binding>KV</binding>
      <description>Stores session context data to enable the 5W1H summary feature</description>
      <schema>
        <key_format>session:{sessionId}</key_format>
        <value>
          <object>
            <field name="fullText" type="string" description="Complete article content"/>
            <field name="chapters" type="array[string]" description="List of article chapter titles"/>
            <field name="subtitle" type="string" description="Original video subtitle text"/>
          </object>
        </value>
        <ttl>3600 (1 hour)</ttl>
      </schema>
    </kv_namespace>
  </database_schema>

  <api_endpoints_summary>
    <pages>
      - GET / — Serves the frontend HTML page
      - GET /public/* — Serves bundled static assets (JS, CSS)
    </pages>
    <api>
      - POST /api/generate — { youtubeUrl, rule? } → SSE stream of article text, X-Session-Id header
      - POST /api/5w1h — { sessionId, chapter } → JSON { who, what, when, where, why, how }
    </api>
  </api_endpoints_summary>

  <ui_layout>
    <section name="Input Area">
      <element>YouTube video URL input field (required, with URL format validation)</element>
      <element>Custom generation rules text field (optional, natural language: task type, style, audience, constraints)</element>
      <element>"Start Generation" button (triggers /api/generate, disabled during active generation)</element>
    </section>
    <section name="Result Display Area">
      <element>Streaming article rendering area with Markdown heading (# for title, ## for chapters) and paragraph formatting</element>
      <element>"5W1H" button next to each chapter heading (## level)</element>
      <element>Collapsible structured summary box per chapter — expands on click, shows Who/What/When/Where/Why/How</element>
    </section>
  </ui_layout>

  <design_system>
    <color_scheme>
      <primary>#2563eb (blue, used for buttons and emphasis elements)</primary>
      <background>#ffffff (light background for optimal reading experience)</background>
      <text>#111827 (dark gray, main text)</text>
      <border>#e5e7eb (light gray, for dividers and borders)</border>
    </color_scheme>
    <typography>
      <font_family>system-ui, sans-serif (cross-platform sans-serif font)</font_family>
      <base_size>16px</base_size>
      <line_height>1.8 (optimized reading experience)</line_height>
    </typography>
    <components>
      <component name="input">Rounded border, light gray background, focus highlight</component>
      <component name="button">Hover effect, disabled state styling (grayed out)</component>
      <component name="chapter_card">Light border, padding to distinguish different chapters</component>
      <component name="summary_box">Light gray background, visually distinct from chapter content</component>
    </components>
  </design_system>

  <key_interactions>
    <interaction>
      <trigger>User enters a YouTube link and clicks "Start Generation"</trigger>
      <flow>
        <step>1. Frontend POSTs to /api/generate with { youtubeUrl, rule? }</step>
        <step>2. Server extracts video ID, fetches subtitles: youtubei.js direct → Webshare TCP proxy → src/fallback-subtitles/</step>
        <step>3. Server builds Gemini prompt (with optional rule constraints), calls generateContentStream()</step>
        <step>4. Server generates a session UUID and sets X-Session-Id in the initial response headers before streaming begins</step>
        <step>5. Server forwards each Gemini chunk to frontend via SSE; simultaneously accumulates full text for KV storage</step>
        <step>6. On stream end, server saves { fullText, chapters[], subtitle } to KV under session:{uuid}</step>
        <step>7. Frontend renders each chunk in real-time, parsing Markdown to detect chapters and inject 5W1H buttons</step>
      </flow>
    </interaction>
    <interaction>
      <trigger>User clicks the "5W1H" button next to a chapter heading</trigger>
      <flow>
        <step>1. Frontend POSTs to /api/5w1h with { sessionId, chapter }</step>
        <step>2. Server reads session context from KV (key: session:{sessionId})</step>
        <step>3. Server calls Gemini with chapter title + full article context to generate 5W1H JSON</step>
        <step>4. Server returns { who, what, when, where, why, how } as JSON</step>
        <step>5. Frontend renders the structured summary in the collapsible box below the chapter</step>
      </flow>
    </interaction>
  </key_interactions>

  <implementation_steps>
    <step number="1">
      <title>Project Initialization &amp; Foundation</title>
      <tasks>
        - Initialize npm project with package.json, tsconfig.json, and Cloudflare Worker types
        - Create wrangler.toml with KV namespace binding, compatibility_date, and esbuild config
        - Create build.mjs for frontend bundling via esbuild
        - Install dependencies: youtubei.js (dev: wrangler, esbuild, typescript, @cloudflare/workers-types)
        - Verify wrangler dev --port 34997 starts without errors
        - Set up src/backend/ and src/frontend/ directory structure
      </tasks>
    </step>
    <step number="2">
      <title>YouTube Subtitle Extraction Module</title>
      <tasks>
        - Verify youtubei.js runs in the Cloudflare Worker runtime — if incompatible, fall back to raw Innertube HTTP calls
        - Implement src/backend/youtube.ts with subtitle extraction via the chosen approach (youtubei.js or raw Innertube)
        - Parse YouTube URLs (youtube.com and youtu.be formats) to extract video ID
        - Implement language fallback chain: zh-CN → zh → en
        - Implement Webshare TCP Socket proxy via cloudflare:sockets connect() for captcha bypass
        - Implement hard-coded subtitle fallback from src/fallback-subtitles/demo.txt
        - Strip timestamp markers and clean subtitle text for AI input
      </tasks>
    </step>
    <step number="3">
      <title>Gemini AI Module &amp; Prompt Templates</title>
      <tasks>
        - Implement src/backend/gemini.ts — Gemini API client for gemini-3.5-flash
        - Implement generateContentStream() for streaming article generation
        - Implement generateContent() for 5W1H structured JSON summary
        - Create src/backend/prompts.ts with article generation prompt template
        - Add optional rule constraint injection (taskType, style, audience, constraint) into prompts
        - Create 5W1H summarization prompt template using chapter context + full article
        - Add error handling with graceful fallback messages on API failure
      </tasks>
    </step>
    <step number="4">
      <title>Session Storage with Cloudflare KV</title>
      <tasks>
        - Implement src/backend/session.ts for KV read/write operations
        - Save session on article completion: key session:{uuid}, value { fullText, chapters[], subtitle }, TTL 3600s
        - Retrieve session by sessionId for 5W1H generation
        - Auto-expire sessions after 1 hour to prevent storage bloat
      </tasks>
    </step>
    <step number="5">
      <title>Worker Router &amp; SSE Streaming Endpoints</title>
      <tasks>
        - Implement src/backend/router.ts — route GET / to serve HTML page
        - Serve bundled static assets from public/ at /public/*
        - Implement POST /api/generate: subtitle extraction → Gemini streaming → SSE response with X-Session-Id
        - Implement POST /api/5w1h: KV context lookup → Gemini 5W1H generation → JSON response
        - Create src/backend/index.ts entry point wiring router + fetch handler
        - Handle CORS headers for cross-origin requests
      </tasks>
    </step>
    <step number="6">
      <title>Frontend: UI, SSE Client &amp; Markdown Rendering</title>
      <tasks>
        - Create HTML page with input area (YouTube URL field + custom rules text field + Generate button)
        - Implement CSS with design system tokens: colors (#2563eb, #ffffff, #111827, #e5e7eb), typography, responsive layout
        - Implement SSE client in vanilla JS — connect to /api/generate, read stream, append chunks to DOM
        - Implement lightweight regex Markdown parser to detect # title, ## chapters, and paragraphs
        - Inject [5W1H] buttons next to each ## chapter heading during streaming
        - Implement 5W1H collapsible summary boxes — POST /api/5w1h then render Who/What/When/Where/Why/How
        - Disable Generate button during active generation; show loading states
        - Validate YouTube URL format on input; show inline error feedback
      </tasks>
    </step>
    <step number="7">
      <title>Integration Testing &amp; End-to-End Validation</title>
      <tasks>
        - Test with demo video (xRh2sVcNXQ8): subtitle extraction → streaming article → chapter rendering
        - Test custom generation rules: verify AI output reflects taskType, style, audience, constraint
        - Test 5W1H summaries: verify correct structured JSON; verify no client re-transmission of article
        - Test fallback chain: simulate direct fetch failure → proxy retry → hard-coded fallback
        - Test error cases: invalid URL, missing subtitles, API key errors, KV unavailability
        - Verify responsive layout on mobile and desktop viewports
      </tasks>
    </step>
    <step number="8">
      <title>Deployment &amp; Go-Live</title>
      <tasks>
        - Create Cloudflare KV namespace via wrangler kv:namespace create
        - Configure Gemini API key and Webshare proxy credentials as secrets
        - Build frontend assets via node build.mjs
        - Run wrangler deploy to publish Worker to production
        - Verify public HTTPS access with no CORS errors
        - Test full flow on deployed URL with demo video
      </tasks>
    </step>
  </implementation_steps>

  <success_criteria>
    <functionality>
      - YouTube URL parsing handles both youtube.com and youtu.be formats correctly
      - Subtitle extraction works end-to-end with the demo video (xRh2sVcNXQ8)
      - Subtitle language fallback chain works: zh-CN → zh → en
      - Streaming article generation produces structured Markdown in real-time via SSE
      - Custom generation rules (taskType, style, audience, constraint) observably influence AI output
      - Chapter detection correctly parses ## headings and injects [5W1H] buttons
      - 5W1H summaries return correct Who/What/When/Where/Why/How for each chapter
      - 5W1H endpoint uses server-side KV context — no client re-transmission of full article
      - Hard-coded subtitle fallback loads correctly when direct and proxy fetch both fail
      - URL format validation shows instant inline feedback for invalid inputs
      - Generate button is disabled during active generation to prevent duplicate submissions
    </functionality>

    <user_experience>
      - Streaming text renders in real-time with typewriter effect — chunks appear as they are generated
      - 5W1H summary boxes are collapsed by default; expand smoothly on click, collapsible again
      - Article layout is clean and readable: clear distinction between headings, paragraphs, and chapters
      - Responsive layout adapts to mobile, tablet, and desktop screen widths
      - Loading states are shown during generation; clear error messages on failure
      - After generation completes, page refresh can still re-query 5W1H summaries via KV (session survives refresh)
    </user_experience>

    <technical_quality>
      - Clean module separation: each src/backend/*.ts file has a single responsibility
      - Gemini API key and Webshare credentials stored as secrets — never exposed to client
      - Cloudflare KV session cache auto-expires after 1 hour (TTL 3600s)
      - SSE streaming uses TransformStream — efficient, backpressure-aware, no memory accumulation
      - Subtitle fallback chain is resilient: direct → proxy → hard-coded; service never fully breaks
      - Gemini API failures return meaningful error messages, not raw stack traces
      - Frontend JS bundled via esbuild with no framework dependencies
      - TCP Socket proxy implementation correctly uses cloudflare:sockets connect()
      - No CORS errors on deployed Worker
      - All TypeScript code is type-safe with no `any` types except at system boundaries
    </technical_quality>

    <design_polish>
      - Design system tokens applied consistently: #2563eb primary, #ffffff background, #111827 text, #e5e7eb borders
      - Typography: system-ui sans-serif at 16px base, 1.8 line-height for comfortable reading
      - Input elements: rounded borders, light gray background, visible focus highlight ring
      - Buttons: hover state change, clear disabled state (grayed out + not-allowed cursor)
      - Chapter cards: subtle border + padding to visually separate sections
      - 5W1H summary boxes: light gray background distinct from chapter content
      - Smooth transitions on summary box expand/collapse and button hover
      - Excellent color contrast for accessibility (dark text on light background)
    </design_polish>
  </success_criteria>
</project_specification>
