<project_specification>
  <project_name>YouTube Subtitle to AI Article Converter - MVP</project_name>

  <overview>
    This project builds a web application deployed on Cloudflare Worker. Users input a YouTube video link with subtitles, and the app organizes the subtitle content into well-structured chapters. By default, the original subtitle content is preserved verbatim — only chapter splitting is applied. When users provide custom generation rules, AI transforms the content per those rules. The app supports real-time streaming generation and chapter-level 5W1H structured summaries. The core product goal is to validate the "video content → structured article" automation workflow, providing content creators and learners with an efficient information organization tool.
  </overview>

  <technology_stack>
    <frontend>
      <framework>Bundled vanilla JS + CSS via esbuild. No SPA framework — bundled modules for clean separation.</framework>
      <styling>Modern Clean CSS (responsive, maintainable, semantic)</styling>
      <state_management>DOM-based state with clean separation</state_management>
      <routing>Single-page application, no routing required</routing>
      <markdown>Lightweight regex parser for chapter rendering</markdown>
      <stream_rendering>SSE streaming DOM rendering (real-time typewriter effect)</stream_rendering>
      <bundling>esbuild bundles src/frontend/ → public/. Worker serves public/ as static assets.</bundling>
      <port>Local: 34997 | Production: Cloudflare Worker hosted</port>
    </frontend>

    <backend>
      <runtime>Cloudflare Worker (production-grade serverless)</runtime>
      <language>TypeScript (type-safe, clean, maintainable)</language>
      <http>Standard Fetch API + Request/Response</http>
      <streaming>TransformStream + SSE (Content-Type: text/event-stream) for real-time AI output</streaming>
      <tcp_socket>cloudflare:sockets connect() for Webshare proxy tunneling (Free plan compatible)</tcp_socket>
      <security>Encrypted secrets via wrangler.toml or Cloudflare dashboard; no key exposure</security>
      <performance>Global low-latency edge network</performance>
      <modularity>Clear module separation — each file has a single responsibility</modularity>
      <testability>Local dev server support (wrangler dev)</testability>
      <port>Local: 34997 | Production: Serverless deployment</port>
    </backend>

    <youtube_module>
      <library>youtubei.js (npm: youtubei.js) — most active Innertube API library</library>
      <caption_fetch>Innertube API — session-based YouTube subtitle extraction via Transcript API + caption tracks</caption_fetch>
      <language_strategy>zh-CN → zh → en (auto fallback chain)</language>
      <proxy>Cloudflare TCP Socket connect() + Webshare.io proxy (anti-captcha)</proxy>
      <reliability>Hard-coded subtitle fallback from src/fallback-subtitles/ (100% availability for demo)</reliability>
    </youtube_module>

    <ai_module>
      <providers>
        <default>Gemini (gemini-2.5-flash) — generateContentStream() + generateContent(). The default AI provider for production deployment.</default>
        <secondary>DeepSeek (deepseek-v4-flash) — OpenAI-compatible chat completions API, 1M context window. Activated via ?provider=deepseek query parameter. No max_tokens limit — model decides output length freely.</secondary>
      </providers>
      <selection_logic>Query-parameter routing: GET/POST ?provider=deepseek → DeepSeek (requires DEEPSEEK_API_KEY secret); otherwise → Gemini (default). Frontend provides a &lt;select&gt; model picker that appends the parameter to fetch URLs. Falls back to Gemini for unknown provider values.</selection_logic>
      <streaming>SSE streaming with sentence-level batching. Tokens are accumulated server-side until a sentence-ending character (。！？\n) or 40-char threshold, then flushed as a single SSE message. Reduces SSE message count from ~1000 to ~50-100 per article. Frontend renders with fadeInUp animation and blinking cursor during streaming.</streaming>
      <prompt_engineering>Dual-format prompt templates: plain text for Gemini, chat messages for DeepSeek. Two generation modes: (1) chapter-only splitting — subtitle is split into chapters with original wording preserved, no rewriting; (2) rule-driven generation — article is generated strictly following user-provided rules. Default output language is Chinese. If the user specifies a language preference in custom rules, that takes precedence. Same requirements, different transport format per provider.</prompt_engineering>
      <response_format>Article text in Markdown (preserved or AI-generated), defaulting to Chinese; plus 5W1H structured JSON</response_format>
      <error_handling>Graceful failure with fallback content; provider-specific error messages (DeepSeek/Gemini distinguished in error output)</error_handling>
    </ai_module>

    <storage_module>
      <service>Cloudflare KV (edge key-value storage)</service>
      <purpose>Session context cache for 5W1H (no re-transmission of full article from client)</purpose>
      <data_schema>Type-safe structured session object</schema>
      <expiration>TTL 3600s (auto cleanup, cost-efficient)</expiration>
    </storage_module>

    <infrastructure>
      <proxy_provider>Webshare.io (free, no credit card)</proxy_provider>
      <proxy_implementation>TCP Socket tunnel via cloudflare:sockets connect() (Worker-compatible)</proxy_implementation>
      <anti_captcha>Auto retry + proxy failover</anti_captcha>
      <deployment>Wrangler CLI + wrangler.toml (Infrastructure as Code)</deployment>
      <environment>Local dev + production parity (no inconsistency)</environment>
    </infrastructure>
  </technology_stack>

  <prerequisites>
    <item>Cloudflare account (for Worker deployment and KV namespace creation)</item>
    <item>Google Gemini API Key (free tier, for gemini-2.5-flash — default production provider)</item>
    <item>DeepSeek API Key (optional, free tier — enables DeepSeek via ?provider=deepseek)</item>
    <item>Webshare.io free proxy account (for bypassing YouTube anti-bot / captcha)</item>
    <item>Node.js + npm environment (local development and dependency installation)</item>
    <item>wrangler CLI (Cloudflare Worker deployment tool)</item>
  </prerequisites>

  <core_features>
    <!-- 1. YouTube Subtitle Extraction Module -->
    <subtitle_extraction>
      - Supports standard YouTube link parsing (youtube.com and youtu.be formats)
      - Prefers Simplified Chinese subtitles; falls back to English when Chinese subtitles are unavailable
      - Direct mode uses youtubei.js Innertube API to pull subtitles directly
      - Automatically switches to Webshare TCP Socket proxy mode on captcha / anti-bot trigger
      - Falls back to built-in hard-coded subtitles from src/fallback-subtitles/ when all else fails
      - Automatically strips subtitle timestamps and irrelevant markers, outputting clean plain text
      - Extracted subtitles are the precondition for chapter detection (/api/chapters) and article generation (/api/generate)
    </subtitle_extraction>

    <!-- 2. AI Content Processing Module (Dual-Mode) -->
    <article_generation>
      - Two generation modes based on whether custom rules are provided:
      - Default mode (no custom rules): Original subtitle content is preserved verbatim. The system detects topic boundaries and organizes text into chapters without modifying any wording. Output is in Chinese unless subtitles are in another language.
      - Default dialogue formatting: When subtitles contain conversation or interview content, the default mode automatically merges same-topic exchanges into a single chapter and formats each speaker's lines with their name prefix (e.g., "Jen:", "Mark:"). Each speaker turn is rendered on its own line within the chapter. If multiple participants join the discussion, their content is organized by topic and formatted individually with name prefixes.
      - Custom rule mode (rules provided): The system generates a new article strictly following user requirements such as task type, style, target audience, language, and constraints.
      - Both modes default to Chinese output; the user can specify a different output language via custom rules
      - Both modes support real-time streaming text generation via the selected AI provider
      - Sentence-level batching: output is accumulated until a natural sentence break or reasonable length threshold, then flushed
      - Frontend renders new content with a smooth fade-in animation as it arrives
      - A blinking cursor indicator appears during streaming and is automatically removed on completion
      - Markdown headings are auto-detected for chapter division
      - Frontend model selector for choosing between available AI providers
      - Shows loading state during generation; provides friendly degradation on failure
    </article_generation>

    <!-- 2.5. Chapter Detection Module (Inline) -->
    <chapter_detection>
      - Chapters are detected automatically from ## Markdown headings in the generated article text as it streams
      - The backend extracts chapter titles from ## headings and stores them in the session for 5W1H queries
      - Chapter titles are normalized: ## prefix and leading/trailing whitespace stripped before storage and matching
      - Frontend renders each ## heading as an h2 element with natural line breaks (no border boxes)
      - After article generation completes, 5W1H action buttons are injected next to each chapter heading
      - Only content from user-selected chapters is included in the final output when selectedChapters is specified
    </chapter_detection>

    <!-- 3. Chapter-Level 5W1H Summary Module -->
    <chapter_summary>
      - Automatically splits the article into chapters based on Markdown ## headings
      - Chapter titles are normalized: ## prefix and leading/trailing whitespace stripped before storage and matching
      - Clicking the [5W1H] button next to a chapter sends sessionId + chapter title to server
      - Server retrieves full article context from KV (no client re-transmission)
      - Generates structured Who/What/When/Where/Why/How summaries via the active AI provider (Gemini or DeepSeek)
      - Summaries rendered in a fixed format: Who, What, When, Where, Why, How as structured JSON
      - Summary boxes are collapsed by default, expand on click
    </chapter_summary>

    <!-- 4. User Interaction & Frontend Experience Module -->
    <ui_interaction>
      - Clean single-page layout divided into input area and result display area
      - Input area: YouTube link field (required), custom rules text field (optional), model selector, and "生成文章" (Generate Article) button
      - Generate button auto-disabled during requests to prevent duplicate submissions
      - Article content with automatic word wrapping and reading optimization, responsive to screen widths
      - Chapter headings clearly distinguished from body text with scroll anchoring
      - 5W1H summary boxes collapsed by default, expand on click
    </ui_interaction>

    <!-- 5. System Stability & Error Handling Module -->
    <error_handling>
      - Invalid link format validation with instant feedback on input errors
      - Subtitle fallback chain: direct → proxy → hard-coded (workflow never breaks)
      - Gemini API failures return clear error messages for easy debugging
      - Auto-rotates through multiple Webshare proxy nodes in proxy mode
      - KV session caches auto-expire after 1 hour to prevent storage bloat
      - After generation completes, session context persists in KV — 5W1H queries work across page refreshes for up to 1 hour
    </error_handling>

    <!-- 6. Smoke Test Module -->
    <smoke_test>
      - A smoke test must be run after every code change to verify core functionality is intact before proceeding
      - The smoke test is a single automated script that covers the critical path end-to-end
      - Smoke test steps:
      - 1. Build frontend assets and start the dev server
      - 2. Verify the HTML page and static assets are served correctly
      - 3. Verify chapter detection works with the demo video and returns a valid chapter list
      - 4. Verify default-mode article generation produces streaming output with chapter headings
      - 5. Verify a 5W1H summary can be queried for a chapter and returns all six fields
      - 6. Verify error handling: invalid URL returns a clear error, missing parameters return 4xx
      - If any step fails, the change must be fixed before continuing to the next feature
      - The smoke test uses the hard-coded subtitle fallback to avoid dependency on external services
    </smoke_test>
  </core_features>

  <database_schema>
    <kv_namespace>
      <binding>KV</binding>
      <description>Stores session context data to enable the 5W1H summary feature</description>
      <schema>
        <key_format>session:{sessionId}</key_format>
        <value>
          <object>
            <field name="fullText" type="string" description="Complete article content"/>
            <field name="chapters" type="array[string]" description="List of article chapter titles"/>
            <field name="subtitle" type="string" description="Original video subtitle text"/>
          </object>
        </value>
        <ttl>3600 (1 hour)</ttl>
      </schema>
    </kv_namespace>
  </database_schema>

  <api_endpoints_summary>
    <pages>
      - GET / — Serves the frontend HTML page
      - GET /public/* — Serves bundled static assets (JS, CSS)
    </pages>
    <api>
      - POST /api/chapters — Accepts a YouTube URL, returns detected chapter list with titles and brief summaries
      - POST /api/generate — Accepts YouTube URL, selected chapter indices, and optional custom rules; returns SSE stream of article text with a session ID header
      - POST /api/5w1h — Accepts session ID and chapter title; returns structured Who/What/When/Where/Why/How summary as JSON
    </api>
  </api_endpoints_summary>

  <ui_layout>
    <section name="Input Area">
      <element>YouTube video URL input field (required, with URL format validation)</element>
      <element>Custom generation rules text field (optional, natural language: task type, style, audience, constraints)</element>
      <element>AI model selector dropdown (Gemini 2.5 Flash default, DeepSeek V4 Flash)</element>
      <element>"生成文章" (Generate Article) button (extracts subtitles + generates article in one click)</element>
    </section>
    <section name="Result Display Area">
      <element>Loading indicator with spinner shown during generation</element>
      <element>Streaming article rendering area with Markdown heading (# for title, ## for chapters) and paragraph formatting</element>
      <element>Chapters rendered as h2 headings with natural line breaks, no border boxes</element>
      <element>"5W1H" button injected next to each chapter heading after article completion</element>
      <element>Collapsible structured summary box per chapter — expands on click, shows Who/What/When/Where/Why/How</element>
    </section>
  </ui_layout>

  <design_system>
    <color_scheme>
      <primary>#2563eb (blue, used for buttons and emphasis elements)</primary>
      <background>#ffffff (light background for optimal reading experience)</background>
      <text>#111827 (dark gray, main text)</text>
      <border>#e5e7eb (light gray, for dividers and borders)</border>
    </color_scheme>
    <typography>
      <font_family>system-ui, sans-serif (cross-platform sans-serif font)</font_family>
      <base_size>16px</base_size>
      <line_height>1.8 (optimized reading experience)</line_height>
    </typography>
    <components>
      <component name="input">Rounded border, light gray background, focus highlight</component>
      <component name="button">Hover effect, disabled state styling (grayed out)</component>
      <component name="chapter_card">Light border, padding to distinguish different chapters</component>
      <component name="summary_box">Light gray background, visually distinct from chapter content</component>
    </components>
  </design_system>

  <key_interactions>
    <interaction>
      <trigger>User enters a YouTube link, optionally enters custom rules, and clicks "生成文章"</trigger>
      <flow>
        <step>1. Frontend validates the YouTube URL format inline; shows error on invalid input</step>
        <step>2. Frontend sends the YouTube URL and optional custom rules to the server</step>
        <step>3. Server extracts the video ID and fetches subtitles through the fallback chain (direct, proxy, hard-coded)</step>
        <step>4. Server determines the mode: if no custom rules, preserve original text and only split into chapters; if rules are provided, generate new content following those rules</step>
        <step>5. Server creates a session and begins streaming the processed content back to the frontend via SSE</step>
        <step>6. Frontend renders article content in real-time: title (h1), chapter headings (h2), and paragraphs</step>
        <step>7. When streaming completes, server saves the full article, chapter list, and original subtitle to KV; frontend injects 5W1H buttons next to each chapter heading</step>
      </flow>
    </interaction>
    <interaction>
      <trigger>User clicks the "5W1H" button next to a chapter heading</trigger>
      <flow>
        <step>1. Frontend sends the session ID and chapter title to the server</step>
        <step>2. Server retrieves the full article context from the session store</step>
        <step>3. Server generates a structured Who/What/When/Where/Why/How summary for the chapter using the full article as context</step>
        <step>4. Server returns the structured summary as JSON</step>
        <step>5. Frontend renders the summary in a collapsible box below the chapter</step>
      </flow>
    </interaction>
  </key_interactions>

  <implementation_steps>
    <step number="0">
      <title>Smoke Test (Run After Every Change)</title>
      <tasks>
        - The smoke test must pass after every code change before proceeding to the next feature
        - Covers: build and dev server startup, static asset serving, chapter detection, default-mode generation, 5W1H summary, and error handling
        - Uses hard-coded subtitle fallback to ensure fast and reliable execution without external dependencies
      </tasks>
    </step>
    <step number="1">
      <title>Project Initialization &amp; Foundation</title>
      <tasks>
        - Initialize npm project with package.json, tsconfig.json, and Cloudflare Worker types
        - Create wrangler.toml with KV namespace binding, compatibility_date, and esbuild config
        - Create build.mjs for frontend bundling via esbuild
        - Install dependencies: youtubei.js (dev: wrangler, esbuild, typescript, @cloudflare/workers-types)
        - Verify wrangler dev --port 34997 starts without errors
        - Set up src/backend/ and src/frontend/ directory structure
      </tasks>
    </step>
    <step number="2">
      <title>YouTube Subtitle Extraction Module</title>
      <tasks>
        - Verify youtubei.js runs in the Cloudflare Worker runtime — if incompatible, fall back to raw Innertube HTTP calls
        - Implement src/backend/youtube.ts with subtitle extraction via the chosen approach (youtubei.js or raw Innertube)
        - Parse YouTube URLs (youtube.com and youtu.be formats) to extract video ID
        - Implement language fallback chain: zh-CN → zh → en
        - Implement Webshare TCP Socket proxy via cloudflare:sockets connect() for captcha bypass
        - Implement hard-coded subtitle fallback from src/fallback-subtitles/demo.txt
        - Strip timestamp markers and clean subtitle text for AI input
      </tasks>
    </step>
    <step number="3">
      <title>AI Module &amp; Prompt Templates (Dual Provider, Dual Mode)</title>
      <tasks>
        - Implement Gemini API client as the default provider
        - Implement DeepSeek API client as an optional secondary provider with larger context window
        - Both providers expose the same capabilities: streaming article generation, structured 5W1H summary, and chapter detection
        - Create dual-format prompt templates supporting both providers' input formats
        - Implement two generation modes: chapter-only splitting (preserve original wording, add headings) when no custom rules; rule-driven generation when rules are provided
        - Build chapter detection prompts that split subtitle text into logical topic segments with titles and summaries
        - Support optional custom rule injection (task type, style, target audience, constraints) into generation prompts
        - Build 5W1H summarization prompt templates using chapter title plus full article context
        - Provider selection via URL parameter, defaulting to Gemini with DeepSeek as opt-in
        - Frontend model selector for switching between available providers
        - Graceful error handling with user-friendly messages on API failure
      </tasks>
    </step>
    <step number="4">
      <title>Session Storage with Cloudflare KV</title>
      <tasks>
        - Implement src/backend/session.ts for KV read/write operations
        - Save session on article completion: key session:{uuid}, value { fullText, chapters[], subtitle }, TTL 3600s
        - Retrieve session by sessionId for 5W1H generation
        - Auto-expire sessions after 1 hour to prevent storage bloat
      </tasks>
    </step>
    <step number="5">
      <title>Worker Router &amp; API Endpoints</title>
      <tasks>
        - Implement request router: serve the HTML page at the root path and static assets from the public directory
        - Implement chapter detection endpoint: subtitle extraction followed by AI chapter boundary detection, returning chapter list with titles and summaries
        - Implement article generation endpoint: route to chapter-only splitting (no rule) or full generation (rule provided) based on request; return streaming response with session ID header
        - Filter content to only include user-selected chapters during generation
        - Implement 5W1H summary endpoint: retrieve session context, generate structured summary, return as JSON
        - Create the main entry point wiring the router and fetch handler
        - Handle CORS headers for cross-origin requests
      </tasks>
    </step>
    <step number="6">
      <title>Frontend: UI, Streaming Client &amp; Markdown Rendering</title>
      <tasks>
        - Build HTML page with input area: YouTube URL field, custom rules textarea (optional), model selector, and single "生成文章" button
        - Apply design system tokens consistently: primary blue for buttons, white background, dark text, light borders
        - Typography: system sans-serif font at readable base size with comfortable line height
        - Implement streaming client that connects to the generation endpoint and appends content to the page in real-time
        - Build lightweight Markdown parser to detect title, chapter headings, and paragraph structure
        - Render chapters as h2 headings with natural line breaks — no bordered chapter boxes
        - After streaming completes, inject 5W1H buttons next to each chapter heading
        - Build collapsible summary boxes that expand on click and show structured Who/What/When/Where/Why/How
        - Disable the generate button during active generation; show loading spinner and blinking cursor during streaming
        - Validate YouTube URL format on input with instant inline feedback
      </tasks>
    </step>
    <step number="7">
      <title>Integration Testing &amp; End-to-End Validation</title>
      <tasks>
        - Test with demo video (xRh2sVcNXQ8): subtitle extraction, chapter detection, streaming output, chapter rendering
        - Test default mode (no rules): verify original wording is kept, only chapter headings are added
        - Test custom rule mode: verify the system rewrites content following user requirements
        - Test custom generation rules: verify output reflects task type, style, audience, and constraints
        - Test 5W1H summaries: verify correct structured output and no client re-transmission of full article
        - Test fallback chain: simulate direct fetch failure, proxy retry, hard-coded fallback
        - Test error cases: invalid URL, missing subtitles, API key errors, session store unavailability
        - Verify responsive layout on mobile and desktop viewports
      </tasks>
    </step>
    <step number="8">
      <title>Deployment &amp; Go-Live</title>
      <tasks>
        - Create Cloudflare KV namespace via wrangler kv:namespace create
        - Configure Gemini API key and Webshare proxy credentials as secrets
        - Build frontend assets via node build.mjs
        - Run wrangler deploy to publish Worker to production
        - Verify public HTTPS access with no CORS errors
        - Test full flow on deployed URL with demo video
      </tasks>
    </step>
  </implementation_steps>

  <success_criteria>
    <functionality>
      - YouTube URL parsing handles both youtube.com and youtu.be formats correctly
      - Subtitle extraction works end-to-end with the demo video (xRh2sVcNXQ8)
      - Subtitle language fallback chain works: zh-CN to zh to en
      - Chapter detection endpoint returns detected chapter list with titles and summaries
      - Default mode (no custom rules): article preserves original subtitle wording, detects topic boundaries, merges same-topic content into chapters, and formats dialogue with speaker name prefixes (e.g., "Jen: content")
      - Custom rule mode (rules provided): generated article strictly follows user requirements
      - Streaming article generation produces properly formatted output in real-time
      - Custom generation rules (task type, style, audience, constraints) observably influence output
      - Chapter headings (##) are rendered as h2 with natural line breaks, no border boxes
      - 5W1H action buttons are injected next to each chapter heading after article completion
      - 5W1H summaries return correct Who/What/When/Where/Why/How for each chapter
      - 5W1H endpoint uses server-side session context — no client re-transmission of full article
      - Hard-coded subtitle fallback loads correctly when direct and proxy fetch both fail
      - URL format validation shows instant inline feedback for invalid inputs
      - Generate button is disabled during active generation to prevent duplicate submissions
    </functionality>

    <user_experience>
      - Single-click flow: user enters URL, optionally sets custom rules, clicks "生成文章" — everything happens in one step
      - Streaming text renders in real-time with typewriter effect — chunks appear as they are generated
      - Chapters are styled minimally: h2 headings with natural line breaks between sections
      - 5W1H summary boxes are collapsed by default; expand smoothly on click, collapsible again
      - Article layout is clean and readable: clear distinction between headings, paragraphs, and chapters
      - Responsive layout adapts to mobile, tablet, and desktop screen widths
      - Loading state shown during generation with spinner; blinking cursor during streaming
      - Clear error messages on failure; app remains functional for retry
      - After generation completes, page refresh can still re-query 5W1H summaries via KV (session survives refresh)
    </user_experience>

    <technical_quality>
      - Clean module separation: each src/backend/*.ts file has a single responsibility
      - AI API keys and Webshare credentials stored as secrets — never exposed to client
      - Cloudflare KV session cache auto-expires after 1 hour (TTL 3600s)
      - SSE streaming uses TransformStream — efficient, backpressure-aware, no memory accumulation
      - Subtitle fallback chain is resilient: direct → proxy → hard-coded; service never fully breaks
      - AI provider API failures return meaningful error messages, not raw stack traces
      - Frontend JS bundled via esbuild with no framework dependencies
      - TCP Socket proxy implementation correctly uses cloudflare:sockets connect()
      - No CORS errors on deployed Worker
      - All TypeScript code is type-safe with no `any` types except at system boundaries
      - Two generation modes cleanly separated: chapter-only splitting (no rewriting) and custom rule generation
      - Chapter detection reliably identifies logical topic segments in subtitle text
    </technical_quality>

    <design_polish>
      - Design system tokens applied consistently: #2563eb primary, #ffffff background, #111827 text, #e5e7eb borders
      - Typography: system-ui sans-serif at 16px base, 1.8 line-height for comfortable reading
      - Input elements: rounded borders, light gray background, visible focus highlight ring
      - Buttons: hover state change, clear disabled state (grayed out + not-allowed cursor)
      - Chapters: natural h2 headings with comfortable top margin to separate sections
      - 5W1H summary boxes: light gray background distinct from chapter content
      - Smooth transitions on summary box expand/collapse and button hover
      - Excellent color contrast for accessibility (dark text on light background)
    </design_polish>
  </success_criteria>
</project_specification>
